<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-04-10T01:43:28+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">JBossWS</title><entry><title type="html">JBossWS 6.2.0.Final is released !</title><link href="/2023/02/14/jbossws-620final-is-released/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="JBossWS 6.2.0.Final is released !" /><published>2023-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2023/02/14/jbossws-620final-is-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/02/14/jbossws-620final-is-released/"><![CDATA[<p>JBossWS 6.2.0.Final is now available for download. In this release, we upgraded the CXF to the latest
4.0.0 release and cleaned up dependencies to run the testsuite against WildFly. In this release, we 
improved the maven pom to use the less environment parameter and profile to build and test.
For more detailed info and full list of issues resolved, please check
<a href="https://issues.redhat.com/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=12310050&amp;version=12396048">release notes.</a></p>

<p>This minor release will be included in WFLY upstream and released in WFLY 28 Beta1.
Please contact us if you get any issue when try with this release. Thanks!</p>]]></content><author><name>Jim Ma</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[JBossWS 6.2.0.Final is now available for download. In this release, we upgraded the CXF to the latest 4.0.0 release and cleaned up dependencies to run the testsuite against WildFly. In this release, we improved the maven pom to use the less environment parameter and profile to build and test. For more detailed info and full list of issues resolved, please check release notes.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Testsuite Transitioned to WildFly CLI scripts</title><link href="/2022/09/28/Testsuite-Transitioned-to-Wildfly-CLI-scripts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Testsuite Transitioned to WildFly CLI scripts" /><published>2022-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2022/09/28/Testsuite-Transitioned-to-Wildfly-CLI-scripts</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2022/09/28/Testsuite-Transitioned-to-Wildfly-CLI-scripts/"><![CDATA[<p>Starting with jbossws-cxf version 6.1.0.Final the testsuite has been
transitioned from using <a href="https://groovy-lang.org/">Groovy</a> scripts to configure the WildFly server
to using <a href="https://docs.wildfly.org/26/Admin_Guide.html#Command_Line_Interface">WildFly’s CLI</a> scripts.</p>

<p>WildFly’s configuration files, standalone-*.xml, are XML based.  Before
the advancements made in CLI scripting, it was more effective to automate
configuration file changes using tools that provided DOM processing utilities.
Groovy was chosen for that task.  But now with a facility in
<em>org.wildfly.plugins:wildfly-maven-plugin</em> to execute CLI script files, it is
more efficient use CLI scripts.</p>

<p>If you have any issue or question, please let us know. Thanks!</p>]]></content><author><name>Rebecca Searls</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Starting with jbossws-cxf version 6.1.0.Final the testsuite has been transitioned from using Groovy scripts to configure the WildFly server to using WildFly’s CLI scripts.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">JBossWS 6.1.0.Final is released !</title><link href="/2022/09/07/jbossws-610final-is-released/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="JBossWS 6.1.0.Final is released !" /><published>2022-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2022/09/07/jbossws-610final-is-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2022/09/07/jbossws-610final-is-released/"><![CDATA[<p>JBossWS 6.1.0.Final has been released and is available for download. In this minor release,
we cleaned up dependencies and fixed couple of issues we found.<br />
For more detailed info and full list of issues resolved, please check
<a href="https://issues.redhat.com/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=12310050&amp;version=12390713">release notes.</a></p>

<p>This minor release has been included in WFLY upstream and will be released in WFLY 27 final.
If you are using JBossWS 6.0.0.Final, please upgrade to this new release. Please contact us if 
you get any issue in this new release. Thanks!</p>]]></content><author><name>Jim Ma</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[JBossWS 6.1.0.Final has been released and is available for download. In this minor release, we cleaned up dependencies and fixed couple of issues we found. For more detailed info and full list of issues resolved, please check release notes.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">JBossWS 6.0.0.Final is released !</title><link href="/2022/06/21/jbossws-600final-is-released/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="JBossWS 6.0.0.Final is released !" /><published>2022-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2022/06/21/jbossws-600final-is-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2022/06/21/jbossws-600final-is-released/"><![CDATA[<p>JBossWS 6.0.0.Final has been released and is available for download. In this major release,
the Jakarta EE 9.1(jakarta namespace aka big bang change) is supported and a lot of
jakarta maven artifacts are included/updated. <br />
For more detailed info and full list of issues resolved, please check
<a href="https://issues.redhat.com/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=12310050&amp;version=12379843">release notes.</a></p>

<p>We now changed the main branch to 6.x as our development branch and created jbossws-cxf-5.6.x branch to maintain 
the javax(Jakarta EE8) namespace future release. For our community developer, please select the base branch to 
create the pull request. If there is any bug fix, we would like to apply this change to both main and javax branches.</p>

<p>If you happen to migrate to jakarta namespace and  use jbossws-cxf, please upgrade to 6.0.0.Final release. 
If you have any issue or question, please let us know. Thanks!</p>]]></content><author><name>Jim Ma</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[JBossWS 6.0.0.Final has been released and is available for download. In this major release, the Jakarta EE 9.1(jakarta namespace aka big bang change) is supported and a lot of jakarta maven artifacts are included/updated. For more detailed info and full list of issues resolved, please check release notes.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">JBossWS 5.5.0.Final is released !</title><link href="/2022/01/13/jbossws-550final-is-released/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="JBossWS 5.5.0.Final is released !" /><published>2022-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2022/01/13/jbossws-550final-is-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2022/01/13/jbossws-550final-is-released/"><![CDATA[<p>JBossWS 5.5.0.Final has been released and is available for download. 
The maven artifacts have been released to the Maven repository. In this release, we upgraded CXF 
to 3.4.5 ,log4j to 2.17.1 and fixed other issues. For more detailed info and full list of issues resolved, please check
<a href="https://issues.redhat.com/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=12310050&amp;version=12357605">release notes.</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Jim Ma</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[JBossWS 5.5.0.Final has been released and is available for download. The maven artifacts have been released to the Maven repository. In this release, we upgraded CXF to 3.4.5 ,log4j to 2.17.1 and fixed other issues. For more detailed info and full list of issues resolved, please check release notes.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Log4j CVE and JBossWS project</title><link href="/2022/01/06/jbossws-log4j-cve/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Log4j CVE and JBossWS project" /><published>2022-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2022/01/06/jbossws-log4j-cve</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2022/01/06/jbossws-log4j-cve/"><![CDATA[<p>After <a href="https://logging.apache.org/log4j/2.x/security.html">log4j cve issues</a> were reported, we carefully
reviewed the usage in JBossWS projects and found we only use log4j dependencies in command line tools, client side
and testsuite. These are places we use log4j dependency:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://github.com/jbossws/jbossws-common-tools/blob/jbossws-common-tools-1.3.2.Final">jbossws-common-tools</a></p>

    <p>It is used to log debug and error messages when running the wsconsume or wsprovide command line tools.
Because these tools only run on the command line and do not run in the JavaEE/Jakarta EE container
server, this CVE issue doesn’t impact the jbossws projects, however
we reviewed the log4j usage in the command line tool and decided to remove this log4j 1.2.14 dependency in 
jbossws-common-tools 1.4.0.Final to 
directly log message to console or use jdk logger.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://github.com/jbossws/jbossws-cxf/tree/main/modules/testsuite">testsuite</a></p>

    <p>This is only for print some log message from our tests. These testsuite maven module won’t be included in 
runtime or used by other projects, so we are safe.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://github.com/jbossws/jbossws-cxf/tree/main/modules/client">client</a> and <a href="https://github.com/jbossws/jbossws-cxf/tree/main/modules/jaspi">jaspi</a> modules</p>

    <p>The log4j is again used to print information for client side like what jbossws-common-tools does, and this CVE issue doesn’t impact 
the client stuff either. To make sure other project including either of this two dependencies doesn’t include the 
old version log4j we upgraded log4j version to 2.17.1 and released jbossws-cxf-5.5.0.Final. In the near future, we’ll
evaluate if it’s possible to remove log4j dependency to directly use jboss logger.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>From above log4j usage in jbossws, if your project has dependency or transitive dependencies to any of these follow projects
please upgrade to jbossws-cxf-5.5.0.Final or jbossws-common-tools-1.4.0.Final. If you find any issue in this upgrade, please 
let us know.</p>]]></content><author><name>Jim Ma</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[After log4j cve issues were reported, we carefully reviewed the usage in JBossWS projects and found we only use log4j dependencies in command line tools, client side and testsuite. These are places we use log4j dependency:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">JBossWS 5.4.4.FInal is released !</title><link href="/2021/05/07/jbossws-544final-is-released/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="JBossWS 5.4.4.FInal is released !" /><published>2021-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2021/05/07/jbossws-544final-is-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/05/07/jbossws-544final-is-released/"><![CDATA[<p>JBossWS 5.4.4.Final has been released and is available for download. The maven artifacts have also been released to the Maven repository.
This is a bug fix release and mainly resolved <a href="https://issues.redhat.com/browse/JBWS-4133">JBWS-4133</a> to support JDK14.
If you moved to JDK14, please try this release and report to us any issues you get.</p>

<p>Thanks <a href="https://github.com/bstansberry">Brian Stansberry</a>’s contribution for this release!</p>]]></content><author><name>Jim Ma</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[JBossWS 5.4.4.Final has been released and is available for download. The maven artifacts have also been released to the Maven repository. This is a bug fix release and mainly resolved JBWS-4133 to support JDK14. If you moved to JDK14, please try this release and report to us any issues you get.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">JBossWS 5.4.3.FInal is released !</title><link href="/2021/04/01/jbossws-543final-is-released/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="JBossWS 5.4.3.FInal is released !" /><published>2021-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2021/04/01/jbossws-543final-is-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/04/01/jbossws-543final-is-released/"><![CDATA[<p>I am pleased to announce JBossWS 5.4.3 Final is out. In this release we upgraded many components as usual and fix several issues to support Jakarta EE9. 
Apache CXF is now upgraded to 3.3.10 and more issues has been fixed in this release.  For more detailed info and full list of issues resolved, please check
 <a href="https://issues.redhat.com/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=12310050&amp;version=12347396">release notes.</a></p>

<p>If you have any problem and want to send feedback for this new release, please post at <a href="https://developer.jboss.org/en/jbossws/cxf">jbossws forum</a> 
or file issues in JIRA at: <a href="https://issues.jboss.org/projects/JBWS">https://issues.jboss.org/projects/JBWS</a></p>

<p>Thanks <a href="https://github.com/ropalka">Richard Opalk</a> for many contributions to this release!</p>]]></content><author><name>Jim Ma</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am pleased to announce JBossWS 5.4.3 Final is out. In this release we upgraded many components as usual and fix several issues to support Jakarta EE9. Apache CXF is now upgraded to 3.3.10 and more issues has been fixed in this release. For more detailed info and full list of issues resolved, please check  release notes.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Move to JBossWS Google Group</title><link href="/2020/05/27/jbossws-new-google-forum/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Move to JBossWS Google Group" /><published>2020-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2020/05/27/jbossws-new-google-forum</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/05/27/jbossws-new-google-forum/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/img/google-group.png" alt="google groups" title="Google Groups" /></p>

<p>JBossWS team has moved the old jboss community wiki and forum to <a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/jbossws">JBossWS Google Groups</a>. The old <a href="https://developer.jboss.org/wiki/JBossWS">JBossWS wiki</a>, <a href="https://community.jboss.org/en/jbossws">User Forum</a> and <a href="https://community.jboss.org/en/jbossws/dev">Developer Forum</a> are all archived and read only now. This change will allow our community users find us more easily with one email or web access. As always, please post your questions, doubts and feedback to google group.</p>

<p>Besides this change, we moved the blog to use github pages jekeyll generator. This is not only for the new content, but also the old blog content from <a href="https://jbossws.blogspot.com/">jbossws blogspot</a>. This again allows everyone can submit PR to add blog entry like the community patch to fix something. If you want to add one blog entry to share your ideas, jbossws usage and other interesting things, please send us a pull request. Create a markdown blog post is very easy and simple, take a look at this <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/posts/">jeykell guide</a> and directly change the content from <a href="https://github.com/jbossws/jbossws.github.io/blob/master/_posts/2020-01-01-jbossws-540final-is-released.md">this post example</a> to create your own will be the all things to do. JBossWS team is waiting for your blog post!</p>]]></content><author><name>Jim Ma</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">JBossWS 5.4.0.FInal is released !</title><link href="/2020/01/15/jbossws-540final-is-released/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="JBossWS 5.4.0.FInal is released !" /><published>2020-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2020/01/15/jbossws-540final-is-released</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/01/15/jbossws-540final-is-released/"><![CDATA[<p>I am pleased to annouce JBossWS 5.4.0 Final is out. In this release we upgraded many components as usual and brings Elytron client configuration support. Apache CXF is now upgraded to 3.3.4 and more issues has been fixed in this release. For more detailed info and full list of issues resolved, please check <a href="https://issues.redhat.com/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?version=12341950&amp;projectId=12310050">release notes.</a></p>

<p>If you have any problem and want to send feedback for this new release, please post at<a href="https://developer.jboss.org/en/jbossws/cxf">jbossws forum</a> or file issues in JIRA at: <a href="https://issues.jboss.org/projects/JBWS">https://issues.jboss.org/projects/JBWS</a></p>]]></content><author><name>JBossWS Team</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am pleased to annouce JBossWS 5.4.0 Final is out. In this release we upgraded many components as usual and brings Elytron client configuration support. Apache CXF is now upgraded to 3.3.4 and more issues has been fixed in this release. For more detailed info and full list of issues resolved, please check release notes.]]></summary></entry></feed>